KIRIKO ANTHONY

Mesa, AZ | Phone: 425-420-6466 | Email: Kiriko.anthony@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/KiriAnthony | GitHub: https://github.com/KiriAnthony |

Portfolio: https://kirisportfolio.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Anti Money Laundering and a life-long dedication to personal improvement. Worked with groups and individually to design and implement full stack web pages. Recognized in prior jobs as a top performer in quality and production goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Applications: Node, Express, SQL, Git, MongoDB, Heroku, MERN Stack Development,

JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, MySQL, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS

PROJECTS

Movies|https://bit.ly/3QpTU9c|https://bit.ly/3cQ50H9

- Movies allows the user to search a year from 1950 to current that will display the top 5 movie, with the inclusion of a fun activity to do while watching built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind framework, IMDb and Bored APIs
- Personal responsibilities include the backend implementation of JavaScript for site functionality and API fetches

MyPantry|https://bit.ly/3KUvNyD| https://bit.ly/3ewopgD

- My Pantry is a virtual list of everything in your pantry allowing users to access a list on the go using Node.js, Express.js, Sequelize ORM, MySQL, BCrypt, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Handlebars, Heroku, and jawsDB
- Personal responsibilities include building the Handlebars.js templates, working on sessions data, and creating frontend routes

WheytsUp | https://bit.ly/3AGUACu | https://bit.ly/3x58Jrb

- WheytsUp allows people to create their own personal workout routines that can be saved and rated using React, graphQL, HTML, JavaScript, and Material UI
- Personal responsibilities include front end layout, styling, and JavaScript functionality for authentication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Freelance

08/2022 - Present

Remote

- Create website designed based on client needs
- Develop and deploy full front and back-end websites using React.js, graphQL, MongoDB, and AWS

Anti Money Laundering Analyst AML RightSource

2021 - 2022

Phoenix, AZ

- Investigate and analyze alerts to draw useful conclusions on the necessity of a SAR filing
- Manage time to ensure production numbers for daily and weekly alerts are achieved and exceeded
- Recognized as top production producer and second quality producer out of team of 30

Shift Manager Starbucks 08/2019-12/2021

Tempe, AZ

- Calculate pars, an inventory system for ordering, based off recorded numbers to reduce the amount of waste while increasing customer satisfaction
- Manage and mentor teams of up to 12 employees to promote a positive workplace in a fast paced environment

 Barista
 08/2016 - 07/2019

 Starbucks
 Monroe, WA

 Communicate with customers to understand their needs and quickly accomplish requests via drink or food orders

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Statistics: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

- Research project: The Effects of Tongue Tie on Breast-Feeding
 - o Data processing using JMP to create a workable dataset
 - Analyzing the cleaned data in JMP by fitting several models to find the best predictive model to show how a procedure to correct tongue-tie in infants impacts breast-feeding